# **ANDY CHEN**

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER

## CONTACT

- +84-24-3215-4352
- ✓ andychen9696@gmail.com
- Train Street 2., Hanoi
- https://andychen9696.github.i o/portfolio/

## **EDUCATION**

2014 - 2019 FPT UNIVERSITY

• Bachelor of Computer Science

#### **SKILLS**

- HTML, CSS
- JavaScript, TypeScript, Python
- React, Next, Vue, Nuxt, React Native, GraphQL
- MaterialUI, TailwindCSS, BootStrap
- NodeJS, NestJS, Laravel,
  Django, Flask
- Web3, EtherJS
- AWS
- SQL, NoSQL

#### LANGUAGES

- English (Fluent)
- Japanese (Fluent)

### **PROFILE**

I am a ambitious professional with a vast of knowledge in different programming languages, responsive frameworks, databases, and code practices. Courteous and enthusiastic with an interest in everything in the orbit and fascinated by web programming such as developing apps. I have established a profound knowledge in React, Vue, ExpressJS, NestJS, SQL, MongoDB, CSS. My experience includes blockchain smart contract(solidity) and connecting wallet to frontend, NFT market place. I am passionate about frontend developments as technology innovation, and I have the drive and energy needed to consistently exceed expectations.

I look forward to being a part of a growing company as a front-end engineer where I can utilize exceptional programming and interpersonal skills acquired to contribute to your company's success

### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### NashTech Vietnam (Hanoi, Vietnam)

Contract (FullStack Engineer)

2023.3 - 2024.2

- Developing user-friendly interfaces with React at NashTech since Feb 2024
- Collaborating with cross-functional teams to deliver optimal solutions
- Applying innovative coding techniques to enhance website performance
- Implemented automated testing processes for mobile applications, reducing the number of bugs by 30% and improving overall code quality by 20%
- Troubleshooting and resolving front-end issues swiftly
- Boosting site speed by 12%, enhancing user experience

#### Solid Engineering Pte (19 Tuas Street, Singapore)

Frontend Engineer

2021.11 - 2023.1

- Developed the hotel booking app using React Native, Google Map Api, AWS and launch the app on Google Store.
- Investigate and implement new design patterns, professional frontend architecture, high-quality performance and security SPA JavaScript Frameworks-React/Next
- Combine SSR (Server Side Rendering) and SSG (Static Site Generating) and improved performance using Next.js
- Define Team code style using ESLint and kept project management at the best level
- · Adapting designing pattern to business needs.

# ReThink (Dubai, UAE)

Frontend Developer Intern

2020.1 - 2021.9

- Worked on a NFT game project using React, TypeScript, NodeJS and Web3
- Developed 10+ new application features and distributed services that support high-scale applications
- Developed a Job Site using React, Redux and optimized images, components for SEO